## PERSONAL DETAILS

Mobile: 0273833901 Website: stewartduffy.com

E-mail: <u>duffy.stewart@gmail.com</u>
LinkedIn: <u>nz.linkedin.com/in/stewartduffy</u>

# **EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS**

2010 Diploma of Digital Media (Media Design School, New Zealand)

Industry Panel Award - Highly Commended for Technical Achievement.

2008 Bachelor of Arts (University of Waikato – New Zealand)

Majoring in Marketing and Screen and Media Studies

## **PROFILE**

**Senior Front-End Developer** with six years commercial experience with a variety of clients in multiple industry sectors, including Data Warehouse, Telecommunication, Travel, Education, Retail, Print Media, Government and Advertising. Core skills include JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, WordPress theme development.

Flexible in working environments having positioned for startups, digital agencies, large corporate and software companies.

Equally as happy getting stuck into a solo project as thrashing out ideas in a cross-discipline team to develop a solution. Enjoys a challenge and strives for continual improvement to develop in better, quicker, more efficient ways which has enabled successful training and mentoring of colleagues.

Excellent communication skills proven through effectively working with people from both technical and non-technical backgrounds. Motivated by bringing designs to life.

Seeks contract work being available from 13th March for starts in Auckland.

### **TECHNICAL SKILL SUMMARY:**

**Job Title:** Senior Front-End / JavaScript Developer

Languages: JavaScript (ES5, ES6), HTML5, CSS3, Sass (SMACSS),

LESS, PHP.

Frameworks / Libraries: ReactJS, Redux, Redux Form, Meteor, AngularJS,

Knockout.JS, Express, Node.js, RequireJS, Google Maps API, Compass, Bourbon / Neat, Material-UI, Twitter Bootstrap, Modernizr, jQuery, PhoneGap, Sencha Touch, CKEditor,

WordPress, High charts.

**Development Tools:** Webpack, Babel, npm, Gulp, Grunt, Raygun, Track:js,

TeamCity, Travis CI, Jenkins CI, Codeship, Codebase, DeployHQ, Adobe Photoshop, Fireworks, Illustrator.

**Automated Testing:** Jest, Enzyme, Mocha, Chai, Sinon, Nightwatch.js (E2E).

**Version control:** Git, GitHub Flow, git-flow, SVN, Mercurial.

**Methodologies:** Agile / Scrum, TDD.

**Databases:** MongoDb, CouchDB, MySQL.

**Operating systems:** Mac OS X, Windows.

## REFERENCES AVAILABLE ON REQUEST

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

## August 2016 – Present (March 2017)

WhereScape, Auckland

Where Scape is an international Data Warehouse Automation & Big Data software company with offices in New Zealand, America, United Kingdom, India & Singapore.

## Senior Developer.

Contracted for 6 months as a React / JavaScript developer to work on the 'Accelerated Metadata Platform', as part of a team of seven. Along with the lead JavaScript developer I am responsible for building and testing the user interface for the Single-Page App that will (once released) be deployed as individual instances on customers own servers. The nature of this setup means that our code is thoroughly reviewed and tested (both unit & E2E).

As this application is still work in progress, features & requirements are often evolving resulting in frequent impromptu planning discussions and tight collaboration with the backend developers, Product Owner & Development Manager.

Many of the components I built for this application were designed to be generic and reusable across the whole app. This approach has aided in reliable testing and helped to enforce continuity for the users and developer.

## **Responsibilities:**

- JavaScript and Front-End UI development as part of a Scrum team.
- Document code using JSDoc and Confluence.
- Research & discuss possible solutions to meet requirements.
- Test and review other developers code.
- Write unit tests using Jest, Enzyme, Sinon.
- Write End-to-End (E2E) tests using Nightwatch.js.

## **Technical snapshot:**

JavaScript (ES6), ReactJS, React-Grid-Layout, Redux, Redux Form, Webpack, Babel, HTML5, Sass (SMACSS), CSS3, Twitter Bootstrap, lodash, GIT, Jira, ESlint, Jest, Enzyme, Nightwatch.js (E2E).

## September 2015 – August 2016

Mighway, Auckland

Mighway is a startup initiative from Tourism Holdings Limited (THL) to provide campervan owners with a platform to enable them to rent their campervans directly to holidaymakers.

#### Senior Developer.

Employed as a Senior Developer to build the Mighway web application, as part of a three person team (later 5), I was involved in building the product from the beginning to the successful initial release three months later. I also initiated the Sherpa project which was a library of reusable React components. After the initial release of the Mighway web application my role has been to continue working on improving and supporting the Mighway application through refining and adding features. I have also had an active role in establishing an Agile development process within the Company and supporting management in recruitment.

As Senior Front-End Developer, I am frequently involved in code reviews and mentoring Junior Developers.

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Full-stack JavaScript and Front-End UI development as part of a Scrum team.
- Lead in UI development, and maintain component library.
- Mentoring junior developers, and participate in code reviews.
- Participate in refinement meetings to scope upcoming stories.
- Cross browser and platform testing.
- Assist in interviewing and on boarding new recruits.

## **Technical snapshot:**

JavaScript (ES6), ReactJS, Redux, Webpack, Babel, npm, Meteor, MongoDb, Node.js, Material-UI, HTML5, Sass (SMACSS), CSS3, lodash, Raygun, Travis CI, JSON, GIT, Jira, ESlint, Stylelint, Mobile-First Responsive Design, Mocha, Chai, Sinon.

Some of the projects I work on at Mighway are:

## **Mighway Core**

https://www.mighway.com

Mighway.com is a platform that allows users to sign up, and either list a camper van to rent, or search for existing listings and book directly from the owner.

This project is a Full-Stack JavaScript single-page application (SPA), built with Meteor, ReactJS and Redux. Material-UI is used to aid with UI components, and for CSS we use Sass (SCSS syntax), and follow SMACSS methodology (Scalable and Modular Architecture for CSS). At Mighway, we follow a strict coding style with a focus on quality and readable code. To help with this, we employ several tools, these being code listing (ESLint, Stylelint), unit testing (Mocha, Chai) and GitHub Flow which ensures that any changes are made in a pull request and subject to a code review.

## Sherpa

Sherpa is part style guide, part UI component library. Sherpa is used as a dependency on mighway.com as well as a number of internal administrative tools. Hosted on private Github and npm, the idea is that one day Mighway will open source this. Built using ReactJS, SCSS and written in ES6 syntax Javascript, compiled with Babel and npm scripts. Sherpa also includes a self-documenting style guide that gives the developer an isolated environment to rapidly build and visually test React components, using React Storybook.

While working on Sherpa, I contributed to the open source project React Storybook. Contributions include updating Webpack configuration, documentation, updating examples, and providing example code to help resolve user submitted issues.

#### March 2015 – September 2015

#### Spark Ventures, Auckland

Spark Ventures is an offshoot of Spark New Zealand (formally Telecom) that focuses on building new business in the form digital experiences. These include Skinny, Big Pipe, Lightbox, Qrious and recently Morepork.

#### Senior Front-End Developer.

Employed as a Senior Front-End Developer to join the enablement team to build and maintain web applications for the other ventures. Primarily working in a scrum team with three developers and one tester, we also worked closely with the wider enablement team to ensure that our development, testing and releases matched the business requirements.

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Participated in refinement meetings to scope upcoming stories.
- Worked on technical grooming documents for project deliverables to consider functional, design and system architecture specifications.
- Cross browser and platform development of software deliverables.
- Front-End development as part of a Scrum team.
- Assisted in reviewing CV's for new applicants, write technical tests and participate in the interview process.

## **Technical snapshot:**

JavaScript, AngularJS, Node.js, Express, HTML5, SMACSS, Sass, Compass, CSS3, Grunt, Bower, Yeoman, Twitter Bootstrap, lodash, Segment, Errorception, Jenkins CI, TeamCity, JSON, AJAX, Photoshop CS5, GIT, Jira, JSLint, Modernizr, Responsive Design.

Some of the projects I worked on while at Spark Ventures are:

- Morepork home security system https://www.morepork.nz
- Bigpipe ISP website https://www.bigpipe.co.nz/
- CSR Toolbox Internal administrative tool to help Customer Service Representatives with provisioning tasks.

## July 2012 - March 2015

## **ELGIN, United Kingdom**

ELGIN's primary product is roadworks.org, a web based service that delivers real-time access to official roadworks information from over 140 public bodies. The services are also embeddable into 3<sup>rd</sup> party web sites, with an API that exposes advanced features and options.

## JavaScript / Front-End Developer.

Employed as a Front End developer to work on the existing roadworks.org web application, and develop the traffic management application. Primarily worked in a team four on this project, but often worked as part of a larger team to focus on the wider business direction. It was standard practice at Elgin to be involved in pair programming and code reviews to ensure the best product is delivered. This role was highly JavaScript orientated with a focus on good quality and maintainable code.

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Scoping of project deliverables and refinement of functional, design and system architecture specifications.
- Research and development with emerging web technologies / frameworks and implement suitable solutions to roadworks.org.
- Cross browser and platform testing of software deliverables.
- Front-End development in both a team and solo environment.
- Worked closely with the Project Manager and Senior Developers to help deliver the best solutions to fulfil both technical and business specifications.
- Participated in regular Scrum and Sprint Planning meetings to discuss development progress, plan next steps and uncover any blocks in progress.
- Track development done in Codebase & Jira against assigned tickets, and commit projects using either GIT or SVN.

# March 2012 – June 2012 (Contract) Front-End Web Developer.

## **Isobar Mobile, United Kingdom**

Contracted as a Front-End Web Developer to work on client project, as part of a team of 25. I worked on a number of projects primarily targeting mobile devices which involved a mixture of Front-End, WordPress and API integration.

## September 2011 – January 2012 Front-End Web Developer.

# Born Digital, New Zealand

Employed as Front-End Web Developer as part of a team of 9, to maintain existing sites as well as develop new projects for clients. I was also responsible for researching new techniques, mainly HTML5 alternatives to flash as most projects needed to work on both desktop and mobile devices. My responsibilities included utilising responsive design techniques to develop sites for clients that span across multiple platforms, act as technical Front-End lead to assist junior Front-End developer with problems, educate other team members and ensure the Back-End and Front-End integrates smoothly with CMS and Database design.

# November 2010 – September 2011 Web Developer.

#### &some, New Zealand

Employed to develop new web sites and applications, maintain existing client's sites. This position involved a mixture of Front-End development and PHP / WordPress development. My responsibilities included supporting, maintaining and updating clients' websites, providing training and on-going support for CMS based products, developing custom WordPress themes and plug-ins and meeting with clients to scope projects.